Alexander Brooks

Software Engineer Atlanta, GA | (708) 427-1732

[Portfolio Link] | github.com/al-brooks | linkedin.com/in/alexander-law-brooks | alexanderlawbrooks@gmail.com

Software Engineer skilled in the conceptualization, planning, and execution of Full-Stack web applications. Interested in designing creative, and unique Front-End Web Development solutions. Past work experience includes 4+ years in Data Analytics within the Healthcare/Benefit Administration industry.

Software Engineering Technologies

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Sass, Node.js, React.js, Express, Redux, PostgreSql, Microsoft SQL Server, Bootstrap, Surge, and Heroku

Education

Digital Crafts | Software Engineering Student | Atlanta, GA | July 2021 - Oct 2021

 16 Week Immersive Full-Stack Software Engineering Program with a focus on developing skills with multiple technological solutions such as static web applications using HTML, CSS and JavaScript, full server-side applications using Node.js, Express and PostgreSql, as well as single-page applications using React.js and Redux.

The Ohio State University | B.S. in Business Administration | Columbus, OH| 2011 - 2015

Software Engineering Portfolio

Musician Brand Site | github.com/al-brooks/xavier-omar-site-redesign | xavier-omar-redesign.surge.sh | September 2021

• Individual React JS/Redux Project that served as a redesign for musician Xavier Omär's personal Brand Site. This web application allows users to view his current discography, music videos, purchase merch, and sign up for an email list.

Movie Scoop | github.com/al-brooks/backend-project | movie-scoop-01284.herokuapp.com | August 2021

- Member of a 4-person Software Engineering team that built a community driven movie review application that allows users to search for their favorite movies and participate through review posting.
- Responsibilities included project management, site design, server and route management, as well as API implementation.

GIFactory | github.com/al-brooks/ui-project | gifactory.surge.sh | August 2021

- Member of a 4-person Software Engineering team that built a GIF search app that allows users to search for GIFs and share them via social media, as well as "like" their favorite GIFs.
- Responsibilities included Project Management, JavaScript functionality and CSS Styling.

Relevant Experience

Digital Crafts | Software Engineering Student | Atlanta, GA | July 2021 - Oct 2021

• Member of July 2021 cohort, designing and crafting full-stack web applications using technologies such as HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, PostgreSql, React.js and Redux.

Bswift | Senior Data Analyst | Chicago, IL | March 2019 - June 2021

- Utilized data manipulation techniques and SQL for client data imports into bswift database.
- Created unique import solutions and logic for ongoing data maintenance, audited data risks and assisted with submitted issues via ticket system.
- Identified and assisted in the creation of new team processes to improve employee utilization of resources.
- Led Microsoft Teams Migration for our EDI department by creating documentation, developing new team sharepoint sites and restructuring our communication process.